Guide to the Anderson Todd architectural academic and career papers, 1943-1995 UA 314
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Anderson Todd architectural academic and career papers
1943-1995
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Todd, Anderson
UA 314
12 Linear Feet (12 boxes and 2 oversize drawers)
5.85 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0314aip_001 (5.85 GB)
The architectural papers of Anderson Todd, AIA, cover his academic career at Rice University as well as his private practice in Houston, Texas.
Biographical / Historical
Anderson Todd was born October 22, 1921. A formative experience in his youth was that at the age of 13, he spent four months sailing and learning navigation on the battleship USS Idaho, which was commanded by his father, Rear Admiral Forde Anderson Todd. From 1939 to 1943 he earned a Bachelor of Arts degree in Architecture at Princeton University. He then served in World War II, commanding convoys in the South Atlantic. After the war he returned to Princeton, where he remained until 1949, earning a Master of Fine Arts degree in Architecture and serving as a Fellow.
In 1949 Todd was recruited by William Ward Watkin, the first professor of architecture at Rice University (then the Rice Institute) to assume a teaching position at Rice. He devoted his entire teaching career to this institution, advancing from instructor to assistant professor in 1952, to associate professor in 1956, and to full professor in 1966. In 1969 he took over the duties of Architecture School Director from William W. Caudill, who had headed the school since 1961. In 1978 he was appointed to the endowed chair the Gus Sessions Wortham Professorship in Architecture. Todd's effectiveness as a teacher was recognized by his being among winners of the university-wide George R. Brown Award for Excellence in Teaching (1968).
Among Todd's accomplishments as an administrator of the school was development of the preceptorship program to be a student's year away from campus working in an established, selective architectural firm. He also started Rice's Qualifying Graduate Workshop, a program that enables students with no undergraduate training in architecture to learn the essential skills quickly and then enter the graduate program, eventually receiving a Master of Architecture degree.
Todd's personal accomplishments as an architect include serving as architectural design consultant for the Ford Foundation's Chilean Communities Facilities Program (1963-64); being a planning consultant for Duke University and Southern Colorado State College (1963-65); working as a partner in Todd Tackett Lacy, Architects and Planning Consultants (1964-69);having his own firm, Anderson Todd, FAIA (1969-72); and being a partner in the office of Anderson Todd, FAIA, and William T. Cannady, AIA. He was elected to Fellowship in the American Institute of Architecture in 1972. His award-winning projects include, in 1966, for the design of his personal residence, an Honor Award from the Houston Chapter of the American Institute of Architects; two Honor Awards from the Houston Chapter of the American Institute of Architects in 1968, one for the design of Houston Fire Station 59, and the other for the Geophysical Laboratory of Superior Oil Company; from the Texas Society of Architects in 1975, the Honor Award for design of the Brochstein House (with Raymond Brochstein and William T. Cannady); and in 1976 from the Texas Society of Architects the Award of Merit for design of the Children's Mental Health Services of Houston (with William T. Cannady). The Superior Oil Company Geophysical Laboratory was also selected as one of fifteen nationwide winners of the "Architectural Award of Excellence for 1968" by the American Institute of Steel Construction.
A significant contribution made by Todd to the civic life of Houston came about when he was a member of the Board of Trustees of the Museum of Fine Arts. He had long admired the style and design principles of Ludwig Mies van der Rohe (1886-1969), and he was instrumental in bringing Mies to Houston to design the 1958 addition to the museum. Todd said, "He was like any other good architect when I recommended him. The museum collection at that time was of high quality but low quantity. We had to rely on visiting exhibitions, so we needed a very flexible space within the rigid structure of the museum. Mies had a free way of handling space, and I found it sympatico."
On October 22, 2011, Todd turned 90. The evening before, a grand dinner was held at Rice University in celebration and honor of his life and work. He died peacefully at home on December 21, 2018.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, photographs, architectural drawings, notes, syllabi and ephemera created or collected by Anderson Todd, FAIA, during the course of his academic career at Rice University and his architectural practice in Houston, Texas.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research except for the Dean Search materials in box 5, folder 13, closed for 35 years from date of creation (until 2013). Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was donated to the Rice University Archives by Anderson Todd in Spring 2013.
Index Terms
Subjects
Architecture; Rice University -- History; Architects -- Texas; Universities and colleges
Document Types
photographs; corrrespondence; drawings (visual works); reports; awards; architectural drawings (visual works)
- Series I: Student life at Princeton, 1943-1948, 164065
  - Class notebooks, handwritten notes, 1940-1942; 164066 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, Jan. 30, 1943, 164067 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Class notes binder, 1946-1947, 164068 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Class notes binder, 1948, 164069 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Princeton Syllabi, 1946-49; 165670 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Princeton Curriculum Notes, 1970s; 165671 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: C.V. and Awards, 1962-1986, 164070
  - Tau Sigma Delta, 1962; 165672 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - C.V., 1984; 165673 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Appointment to Wortham Chair of Architecture, 1978; 165674 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brown Award for Superior Teaching, 1968; 165675 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Awards, 165676 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - TSA Educator Award, 1986; 165677 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series III: Photos of Todd, doodles, notes and ephemera, ca. 1950-1995, 164072
  - Photos of Todd, family and colleagues, 165681 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notes and Fragments, 165682 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Doodles and drawings, 165683 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Notes/doodles/fragments, 165684 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series IV: Correspondence and speeches, 165841
  - Correspondence-1950s, 165685 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence-1960s, 165686 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence-1970s, 165687 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence-1980s, 165688 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence-1990s, 165689 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence-n.d., 165690 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Thoughts and Quotes, 165691 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Collected Ephemera, 165692 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Span Computer/Beam computer, 165693 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Flyer for Wray Ranch and Wilderness Space Station, Columbus, TX, 165694 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Speech: Morality of Logic-the Logic of Morality, 165695 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Speech: From Polliwog to Pedagogue-or, The Education of an Architect, 1984; 165696 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Speech/eulogy: Huge V. Neuhaus "Noblesse Oblige", 165697 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Speech: Mies van der Rohe and Louise Kahn, 165698 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Speech notes, 1987; 165699 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Series IV: Projects, 1960s-1970s, 164071
  - Brochstein home (5307 Queensloch, Houston, TX), 165705 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Center for the Visual Arts (Houston, TX), 1967; 165706 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cohen House proposed additions, Rice University, 1970s; 164648 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Crozer Dormitory (Chester, Pennsylvania)-proposal, 1965; 165708 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Crozer Dormitory (Chester, Pennsylvania) specifications, 164649 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Crozer Dormitory (Chester, Pennsylvania), working documents and correspondence-Part 1, 1967-1969; 164651 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Crozer Dormitory (Chester, Pennsylvania) - working documents and correspondence- (Part 2), 1969-1970; 164652 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Crozer Foundation Planning Study for Crozer Theological Seminary and Crozer-Chester Medical Center, Pennsylvania, 164650 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Duke University design study, 165709 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fairchild Camera: Navajo Housing Project, 1971; 165710 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fire Station #59, Houston, TX, 1968; 165711 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Memorial Lutheran Church, Houston, TX, 165712 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Ben Mosier, 1970; 165713 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Todd Residence-Shadowlawn, 165714 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Small house designs for lot on Hazard (Houston), 165715 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - South Colorado State College, 1963; 164653 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Southern California State College, 165716 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - contract, 1966; 164661 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - billing Rapp Tackett Flash, 164654 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - billing and estimates, 1974-1975; 164655 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - certificate and application for payment, 1969; 164656 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - contractor Letters of Transmittal, 1970; 164657 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - specifications, contract set, March 8, 1969, 164658 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - survey notes, 1969; 164659 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - specifications and sub-contractors, 1969; 164660 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - recap of expenditures, 1969; 164662 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - correspondence, 1969-1970, 164671 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - punch list, 1970, 164668 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - concrete coring, 1971-1972; 164666 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - photos of site, including Anderson Todd inspecting formworks, 164664 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - design awards documents, 1972-1973; 164669 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - notes and drawings, 1973-1974; 164663 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - drawings and photographs, 1974; 164670 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Suit residence (1828 Dunstan, Houston, TX) - contract, 1974; 164665 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Suit residence - Chuck Redmon transmittals, Weston, Mass., 1974; 164667 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Superior Oil Company Geophysical Laboratory (Houston, TX), 1968-1969, 164672 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Tennis Club, 165717 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Todd Tackett Lacy firm dissolution agreement, 1968; 165718 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Series V: Rice courses, 1950-1994, 164826
  - Arch 200/300, Programs and Problems, 1950; 165719 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - History of Art 415, 1957; 165720 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Renaissance and Post-Renaissance Architecture, 313, ca 1957, 165721 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - History of Art, 315, 1956-59; 165722 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Todd's curriculum notes, 1960; 165723 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - curriculum, 1960s, 165724 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Structure, 1960s, 165725 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Arch 500, 1962; 165726 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Arch 100, 1963; 165727 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Arch 400, 1963; 165728 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Arch 500, 1963; 165729 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Arch 500-Seminar, 1963-64; 165730 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 500 Seminar, 1963-64; 165731 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Arch 300, 1964; 165732 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Seminar Arch 500, 1964-65, 165733 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Arch 500, 1964-65; 165734 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Arch 600, Houston Sports Arena, 1965; 165735 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Faculty Kit, notes for Architecture at Rice on Curriculum, 1965-66, 165736 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Class Problems, 1965-66; 165737 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Class Schedules, 1967-68, 165738 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Arch 200, Spring 1968; 165739 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Preceptee Report, 1969-70; 165740 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Curriculum, 1970s, 165741 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Arch 412b-Readings in Design Theory, 1970; 165742 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Arch 412b, Special Projects, 1972-73; 165743 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Special Projects-A Study of Alternatives in High Rise Buildings, 1976; 165744 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Arch 302b, Spring 1976, 165745 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Art School Primer, Arch 202b, Jan. 1978, 165746 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Arch 302/402b, Spring 1980, 165747 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Arch 302/402 Studio, 1982; 165748 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Arch 302b, 402b Junior/Senior Studio, Spring 1984, 165749 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Arch 100b, 1987; 165750 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Arch 102b, Spring 1988, 165751 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Design Thesis Review, 1988; 165752 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Studio 235, Jan. 1989, 165753 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Evaluations of A. Todd's courses at Rice, 1989-90; 165754 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Arch 300/400s Structure, Spring 1989, 165755 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Student Projects Review, 1990-91; 165756 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Arch 501, 1991; 165757 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - 602-603 High rise elevators, 1991; 165758 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Arch 600/003 High Rise Studio, 1992; 165759 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Arch 602, Design Studio, 1992; 165760 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Arch 602-003, High Rise Studio, 1992; 165761 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Arch 602, Design Studio, 1992; 165762 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Arch 602-603, High Rise design, 1992; 165763 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - HART 319 Gothic Art and Arch in N. Europe, 1993; 165764 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - History of Modern Architecture, Spring 1994, 165765 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reading lists, 165766 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Seminar, n.d., 165767 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Possible class material, 165768 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Rice Qualifying Graduate Workshops (QGW), 1973-1992, 164846
  - 1973-74, 164850 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1975-76, 164851 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1978-79, 164852 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1979-80, 1979-89; 164853 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1981-82, 164854 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1982-84, 164855 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1982-83, 164856 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fall 1983, 164857 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 1984-85, 164858 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 1984, 164859 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1985-86, 164860 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 1987-88, 164861 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 1988-89, 164862 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - 1989, 164863 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1989-90, 164864 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 1990-91, 164865 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Fall 1990, 164866 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - 1992-1993 Statements of Intent, 1992-93; 164867 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 1991-92, 164868 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Lettering Exercises, 164869 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - General Tools, 164870 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Series VII: Rice School of Architecture administration, 1957-1992, 164847
  - AIA Corporate Membership, 1957; 165769 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Overall architecture program, 1959-1960; 165770 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Universidad Autonoma de Guadalajara, Mexico, 1964; 165771 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Faculty, 1964-65; 165772 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "Graduate Kit", 1965-66; 165773 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Todd sabbatical, 1965-66; 165774 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Graduate program/Faculty areas of interest, 1967-68; 165775 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Executive Committee, 1967-68, 1967-69; 164871 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1968-69, 164872 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - AR5 Conference notes, 1969; 165776 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Directorship-congratulations, 1969; 165777 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Faculty Meeting, 1969-1970; 165778 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Caudill memo on technology, 1969; 165779 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Proposal for Graduate Studies in Architecture, 1971; 165780 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Graduate Committee, 1971, 164874 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - First day of school notes and memos, 1970-71 assembly, 164875 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Hackerman Inauguration, 1971, 164876 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Advisory Selection Committee, 1971, 164877 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - AIA Fellowship Nomination, 1971; 165781 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - David Crane letter of understanding regarding architecture program, to Pres. Hackerman, 1972; 165782 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Rice University Planned Gifts Committee, 1972, 164878 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate and graduate committees, 1973; 165783 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Preceptorship program B, 1973, 164879 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Accredidation visit, 1976, 164880 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Wortham Professorship correspondence, 1978, 164881 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Anderson Hall Remodeling, 1979-80, 164882 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Affairs Committee, 1980, 164883 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Accredidation, 1981; 165784 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Examinations and standings, 1982-83, 164884 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Thesis tracks (notes), 1985-86, 164885 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Faculty search, 1985-86; 165785 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Dean search (RESTRICTED), 1987-88; 165786 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Bob Irwin/Cullinan Chair Committee Meeting, 1987-89, 164886 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cullinan Chair, Koolhaas, 1992; 165787 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Series VIII: Non-Rice groups, 1960s and undated, 164848
  - Art Associates of St. Thomas, 1966; 165788 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - MFA, 165789 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - MFA/ Mies Dander Rake Wing, 165790 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - MOMA, 165791 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Fellowship A.T. (F.H.I.A.), 165792 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Museum of Fine Arts Houston, 1969; 165793 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Planned Parenthood, 165794 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Contemporary Art Museum (Houston, TX), 165795 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, School of Art, 165796 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Museum School (Glassell), 165797 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - CMHSH, 165798 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - MFA board and Dixon Bennett (school), 165799 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, Architecture and Environmental Arts Program, 165800 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 7th of April Club, 165801 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Urban Research Center, 1964; 165802 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Series IX: Subject files, 1960s-1992, 164849
  - Chairs (Furniture), 165803 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - JB Jackson, 165804 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Illinois Institute of Technology, 1974; 165805 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Work by A. Alp, 165806 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Louis Kahn of Rice, 165807 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Union of Virginia, 165808 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Spiro Kostof (d. 1991), 165809 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - DeMenil, 1969, 165810 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Jean Labatut (Princeton), 165811 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Hugo Neuhaus, Jr., 165812 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - FJ Denis Beaty, 165813 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Charles Schorre, 165814 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Richard Ingersoll: Cities and History, 1986-87; 165815 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Travel-France, 165816 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Chile - Argentina, 167148 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Series X: Slides and Photographs, 1949-1988, 163977
  - International Travel, 165223
    - Rome, Sienna, Florence, July 1949, 165232 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Chichen-Itza, Jan. 1951, 165233 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mexico City, Jan. 1951, 165234 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sens, Autun, Tournus, Pimonial, Nov. 1955, 165235 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Austira, Rome, Athens, Dec. 1955, 165236 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Thebes, Luxor, Dec. 1955, 165237 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sicily, Jan 1956, 165238 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Riviera Frescoes, Jan 1957, 165239 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - unidentified art (Istanbul?) Nov. 1958, 165240 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Fireworks, Herkommen Hospital, Stuttgart, June and July 1962, 165241 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Ise, Nara, Toba, Japan, May 1966, 165242 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Tokyo, May 1966, 165243 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Chandigarh, June 1966, 165244 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Fatephus Sikri, June 1966, 165245 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Hong Kong, Singapore, Bangkok, June 1966, 165246 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - India, June 1966, 165247 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - India, Bangkok, June 1966, 165248 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Iran, June 1966, 165252 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Srinagar and Chandigarh, Sep 1966, 165249 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Byblos, Baalber, 1966, 165250 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Kyoto, 1966, 165251 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Berlin, Hilversum, May 1967, 165253 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - East Berlin, May 1967, 165254 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Europe, Ektachrome, May 1967, 165255 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Tapiola, May 1967, 165256 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Expo 67, Czech Mosaic, nite shots, Aug 1967, 165257 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - unidentified, 1967, 165258 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Ontario Place, July 1971, 165259 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Athens, Acropolis, Lisbon, Santiago, Nov 1972, 165260 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Giza, Saqquara, Karnak, Egypt, Nov 1972, 165261 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Galtieres, 1975, 165262 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Pommard, Novay, Arc of Senans, 1975, 165263 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Unidentified, 1975, 165293 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Fontainbleau, May 1976, 165264 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Savlieu Vezelay, May 1976, 165265 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Neresheim, June 1976, 165266 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Tubingen, Stuttgart, Vierzehn, June 1976, 165267 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Machu Picchu, April 1977, 165268 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Ireland, Nov 1977, 165269 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Stuttgart, Pforzheim, Mannifeim, 1977, 165270 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Europe, Fall 1977, 165271 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Europe/Ireland, Fall 1977, 165272 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Dublin, 1977, 165273 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - France, 1977, 165274 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Munchen, Zwiefalten, 1977, 165275 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Unidentified, 1977, 165321 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - England, 1981, 165276 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Germany, Italy, 1981, 165277 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Germany, 1981, 165278 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Italy, 1981, 165279 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Italy, England, 1981, 165294 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Unidentified, 1984, 165322 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Albuquerque, Munchen, Die Wies, Zurich, June 1985, 165295 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Die Wies, La Tourette, Zurich, House of Man, LEC June 1985, 165296 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Moissac, Toulouse, Montpellier, "Antigone," June 1985, 165297 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Montpellier, Aix En. P., Turnino, Vigevano, June 1985, 165298 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Paris, Versailles, Anet, Chartres, Loches, Montparnasse, June 1985, 165299 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - St. Emilion, Monpazier, Toulouse, Carcassonne, June 1985, 165300 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Versailles, June 1985, 165312 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Villandry, d'Usse Ichinon, Fonteuvaud, Pgitiers, Perigeux, June 1985, 165301 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Arezzo, Firenze, Lucca, Nice, La Roquette, July 1985, 165302 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Italy, Neuri, Egypt, Greece, July 1985, 165303 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Krefeld, July 1985, 165304 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Silva Cane, Firming, St. Etienne, 1985, 165305 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Stuttgart, 1985, 165306 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Urbino, Gubbio, Assisi, 1985, 165307 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Venezia, 1985, 165308 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Villanors, Azay-Le Rideau, 1985, 165309 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Unidentified, 1985, 165323 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Chenonceaux, Mont St. Michel, 165324 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Cluxers, 165325 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Dulles, 165326 (Box 7, Folder 4)